Ireland, 1916. His Dreams Inspired Hope. His Words Ignited
Passion. His Courage Forged A Nation's Destiny.
Michael Collins is a war, drama, thriller film directed by Neil Jordan.
Michael Collins plays a crucial role in the establishment of the Irish Free State in the 1920s, but
becomes vilified by those hoping to create a completely independent Irish republic.
Michael Collins, played by Liam Neeson.
Harry Roland, played by Aidan Quinn.
Ned Broy, played by Stephen Rea.
Eamon de Valera, played by Alan Rickman.
Kitty Kiernan, played by Julia Roberts.
Joe O'Reilly, played by Ian Hart.
Michael Collins is a 1996 biographical historical drama film about Michael Collins, a leading figure
in the early-20th-century Irish struggle for independence against the United Kingdom.
It is written and directed by Neil Jordan and stars Liam Neeson in the title role,
along with Aidan Quinn, Stephen Rea, Alan Rickman, and Julia Roberts.
The film was distributed by Warner Bros.
An international co-production between Ireland, the United States, and the United Kingdom,
Michael Collins was one of the most expensive films ever produced in Ireland.
Filming took place in Dublin, and the score was composed by Elliot Goldenthal.
Michael Collins won the Golden Lion at the 53rd Venice International
Film Festival, with Neeson winning the Best Actor Award.
It received a limited release in the United States on 11 October
1996, before going to a wide release on 25 October.
It was released in Ireland on 8 November.
It received generally positive reviews, and was nominated for Best Original
Score and Best Cinematography at the 69th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of civil war, fight,
presidential election, freedom fighter, biography.
The tone is emotional and intense.